<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | James Briant</title><link>https://james.briant.co.uk/project/</link><atom:link href="https://james.briant.co.uk/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://james.briant.co.uk/media/icon_hua3e57709ee188cd8ce6fd9a15087a1ec_6928_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://james.briant.co.uk/project/</link></image><item><title>Bayesian Calibration</title><link>https://james.briant.co.uk/project/calibration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://james.briant.co.uk/project/calibration/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project aims to extend the &lt;a href="https://rss.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/1467-9868.00294" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kennedy &amp;amp; O’Hagan (2001)&lt;/a> Bayesian Calibration for Computer Models framework by employing advanced computational and latest MCMC techniques.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary goal is to calibrate the UK Met Office&amp;rsquo;s high resolution &lt;a href="https://www.metoffice.gov.uk/research/approach/modelling-systems/unified-model" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unified Model&lt;/a> using large volumes of data from multiple sources. Intermediate steps will focus on calibrating a far simpler model, likely a nuclear fusion simulation from &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/uk-atomic-energy-authority" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UKAEA&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In collaboration with Dr. Matt Graham (UCL), Dr. Mariya Mamajiwala (Sheffield) and Prof. Serge Guillas (UCL).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Embedding High Resolution Variability into a Climate Simulation</title><link>https://james.briant.co.uk/project/clouds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://james.briant.co.uk/project/clouds/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project is developing a novel method to improve representation of cloud formation in climate models. Our method changes the simulated climate and reduces bias in hindcasts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pre-trained Gaussian Processes learn the temperature and specific humidity fields from high a resolution weather forecast. During the climate model run-time, Gaussian Process predictions add perturbations to climate model fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In collaboration with Dr. Dan Giles (UCL), Dr. Cyril Morcrette (UK Met Office) and Prof. Serge Guillas (UCL). An initial paper being readied for submission in early 2024 and more details will be available here after pre-print is available on Arxiv.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upper Atmosphere Modelling with Uncertainty Quantification</title><link>https://james.briant.co.uk/project/space/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://james.briant.co.uk/project/space/</guid><description>&lt;p>This long term project uses Gaussian Process emulation and Bayesian Calibration to aid the extension of the Met Office&amp;rsquo;s Unified Model into the upper atmosphere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Unified Model has a huge computational requirement to run, but also significant expense if required for the design of experiments to building emulators of the weather forecast model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In collaboration with Prof. Anasuya Aruliah (UCL), Prof. David Jackson (UK Met Office) and Prof. Serge Guillas (UCL).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>